I have my volume down so I can hear my
echo so here we'll have to remind me of
the questions again but yeah because
otherwise I'm gonna try to answer
everything and then my brain can't do
that
so okay it's quite quite a quite a lot I
guess with the inspiration for your
project what inspired your project the
inspiration for my project is I don't
think there is one singular X
inspiration it's just who I am
every interest of mine culminated in a
way that I think can vastly improve life
on this planet together for the
individual for the group for the world
itself so it's all like I said all of my
interests just happening to come in into
play which also makes me start to think
that everyone has that everyone has a
purpose something that brings all
everything they've ever done a bit
interest in every like every experience
into who and what they are and so that
was a but that is that is my inspiration
I'd answer that question the same way
really but then I guess so
what's your project about the project
you're working on now and and what
progress have you made on it so I had
the vision slash idea for a technology
cooperative and what that can and would
do for Humanity years ago and because I
besides that I can't really explain to
you why it's the solution all of
humanity unless you can see that right
it's hard to give somebody the full big
picture of what that can do unless
you're able to have a conversation and
so remind me of the question again just
just what your project was about and
thank you thank you just keep it really
that so what the project so I the
technology cooperative but because I
wasn't able to explain it in a white
pages or explain it in one succinct way
I just had to keep putting it out there
to the best of my ability and it's
improved the the project
itself and how much it solves and how
complex and non complex it is and where
it is right now is it is it's a B that's
together tack and we meet every Friday
me Bentley and Adriel we're kind of the
board of directors at the moment and
it's more of a meta project under the
game B umbrella do you know game B no no
okay most of the people I talk to you
90% of the time or part of game B so
that's like getting into that's a whole
other whole other thing but what's my
point of game B my project
oh that's how I meant Bentley and then
Adrian was my brother but he finally
came on board once I was involved with
game B it gave me a nutshell is
basically game aids everything up to
this point in history and it's self
terminating so we need a game B is the
simplest way to explain that and then
there's some under scenarios that like
that it would be anti rival wrists and
Omni win I'm sure there's other ones
that I missing but that is part anyway
that's what game B is because it'll
probably come up I mean feel free to ask
questions because I realize that was not
the best of an explanation but my
project is the idea of a solutions is a
solution slash tech cooperative and I
have other people are helping create it
but because of the grandness of it we
are focusing on making bringing project
holders together because everyone in
game B or a bunch of people in game B
who are drawn into game B had a project
of their own their own world-changing
idea their own little piece of that or
big piece of it and so no one really
wanted to go on everyone else's and it's
hard for anyone who wants to go on to
kind of be able to tell the difference
between them so we are bringing the
project holders together and figuring
out tools we can create to help
facilitate our projects so in my mind
that's creating common finance and
marketing and the tools we need to be
able to do the things that right now
costs a lot of money through technology
and we're meeting every Friday and
having those comforts
and we just had our right we have like a
mastermind group of projects on
Saturdays and then on Friday is free
either moving the project forward with
the board meeting like the meta project
the project projects or we're having a
conversation with people in their
projects about their project like we're
doing an idea cafe on it Edea cafe is my
older project it was the closest
iteration I had to something I was
capable of doing in the right direction
it was idea cafe which is like a
hour-long conversation where everyone
takes up to five minutes to answer the
question the conversation on there every
conversation is a question and everyone
takes a turn answering the question
without interruption for up to five
minutes then you have an open
conversation for the rest and although I
enjoy those I wanted them on zoom and I
wanted them to be bigger I wanted and I
didn't really want them to be on their
own YouTube channel I just wanted to
have the conversations and so I have one
tomorrow we'll see if people show up
because I'm asking a question I that's
its own project um everything's a
project everything has a name and
everything has it anyway and so right
now my project is solutionizing so it's
a different hour-long conversation where
we generate an actual potential solution
together within an hour so we spend 15
minutes talking about what what is
currently happening in that space what
works and what doesn't then 15 minutes
talking about our ideal version of the
future what would we love this to look
like in a perfect world and then we
spend 30 minutes talking about what
could we actually create together if we
had 10,000 people and $100,000 what
could we do with that right now together
and we've done like some of them so far
on things like transportation and we
just did one on mental health and
education in the food system and they've
been really amazing conversations and
again I mean the conversation itself is
the point but so is the stuff that's
generated through it the idea the idea
is itself that we could actually make
this thing together and I'm figuring out
how to
bring people into the process to create
the process how do we create a process
to create something with ten thousand
people how do we recruit ten thousand
people how do we involve ten thousand
people in the process so that it's
rewarding for everybody and we can get
the idea out into the world so that is
what solution raising is idea Cafe is a
bit of a old project it might come back
to play I do and then together tech it's
not just mine either solution reason
really but it is the tech cooperative
and I think you frozen did I lose you
okay are you there
here yeah just gonna drop you down and
back up because your videos frozen I'm
hoping that unfreezes or just your
videos up now it's a black screen before
it was a frozen screen so did you get
what I said about the projects I missed
I missed a bit of it do you know which
bid it was did you get what a solution
raising was that's probably my important
part because it's what I'm focused on at
the moment
solution raising so I mean okay have you
ever heard of a poppy do ever pepper
pedia like appropriate technology as
what its Titsworth stands for I mean
there's so solution raising I know that
that's a real challenge isn't it because
people just just want the thing right
not necessarily to dig deep into and to
how things work and why things are the
way they are and so on yeah which is
if we design it for those people
included right that if that is the
10,000 people and there's maybe a
thousand or a hundred of those people
who want to actually dig into the
process and create it and there's asking
questions and doing other things to the
to the greater group of people but yeah
it has to
that's why it has to be designed with
and forth people for the people
participating in it and if you take
10,000 random people how many want to be
involved level how do we get 10,000
people we might mean 10,000 of those
hundred people in order for them to be
wanting to be on the first iteration
project that actually involves how many
people and there'll be these many layers
many levels and layers and for them like
or not if there was five of us we can
figure out how to generate a system for
10,000 people and try it it could be our
first iteration but my guess is it'll be
more about five people finding a process
400 people a hundred people getting
together and figuring on a process for a
thousand the thousand people going out
and having teams of ten and like it's
about figuring it out how you grow it
and how do you get it to scale to the
point where either a contest a project
involves 10,000 people and then you has
it really dirty I was out the garden
earlier having it like whether it use
just a process that involves 10,000
people or whether it could scale so that
you could have 10 million people on a
project is a question will have to
answer together like I don't know which
one I have ideas for both but um it
depends on which one is more rewarding
for the most people and how much
diversity we need in ways to participate
in a ways to contribute and it's about
making a process that was enjoyable for
the vast majority of people to
participate in so I think it means to be
you like so so this would require what
engineering and I mean user interface
designers yeah I mean it would be a tech
company most of the solutions we come
with in solution raisins are tech not
all of them but they're at least
enhanced with technology yeah so I guess
it would be like how do you attract
because I've
I've tried to scour the internet to try
to find user interface people and
open-source people and those that are
interested in and/or familiar with like
things like project cybersyn at a chili
you know the resource-based economy
people the site guys I do know that I
didn't know cyber saying before today
but I and I barely know it now but I do
know it's like Geist and resource based
economy and it was essentially just I
mean the zeitgeist essentially a
continuation of that idea but um you
know I see that as far as the
participation or and that is limited
because of lack of funding or you know
like just lack of attraction to the idea
but now we have a very interesting
opportunity here being isolated to to
actually create these sorts of systems
to to model the world and to use
robotics in this in this particular case
not just a not to make things more
efficient which was was it was kind of
my view and also you know less impactful
in the environment to to regenerate the
environment but uh and also Elsa you
know not to be exploited through through
labor and work and so on and like as a
replacement Apple ISM so yeah I just
this is quite an opportunity to to
actually do those things it doesn't seem
that ridiculous to have have a system
that can make and model everything
happening in the world I mean in one
example like with ventilators there's
there's a lack of ventilators and if we
had if we had a cybersyn or a
resource-based economy uh what kind of
word do you like to use for this cuz
there's there's you know for the system
I mean I I'm fond of calling it just the
interface I mean it's essentially the
internet is what the internet needs to
become needs to become a part of the
internet I don't I mean I have a vision
of the future one that are moving into
but which is very much tied to
resource-based economy that is what I
think we do generate together but I'm
not tied to the outcome I'm tie I want a
process that we co-create a better
outcome way and we continually improve
it and there is no point like we I was
listening to this I think if Jamie vo
the talks about how in a utopia the
reason utopias can't exist is that you
maximize when you maximize for any
single variable or value you're gonna
have diminishing returns and it's gonna
cost you everything else in society so
if your highest thing is justice your
highest thing is peace it's gonna cost
you everything else because you're gonna
optimize to that to the nth degree and I
think something like a resource-based
economy might be keeping that in in like
this is what this is how we live like
that and so let's create that instead of
how do we improve how do we create a
system of cooperation Omni win from
where we are how do we meet how do we
meet people's needs now how do we
co-create solutions that we want to be a
part of and how do we keep moving in the
direction of in my mind getting to
resource-based economy but everyone
might have their vision of the future
they're living in - and it's just a
resource-based economy was the simple
answer to your question sorry I
appreciate that appreciate that so I
guess I guess yeah everyone's used and
cultures and ways of living and and you
know family dynamics you know and that
needs to be accounted for in this system
I mean I think it eventually will just
be called the internet you
we won't really call it a resource-based
economy here or cybersyn 2.0 but just
just as far as the manipulators like the
the means of control through through
money it's like and those that control
this this manipulation tool of finance
it's uh is what's prevented it from
happening uh I mean you know if like the
CIA didn't step in during the Allende
regime and and or the the pink wave in
South America was allowed to continue
without you know sanctions or and
espionage then are you there Jubilee
okay and then uh yeah it'd be it did you
interesting to see what the world was
like I mean there was can hear me
Jubilee yeah I can hear you my kids
making noise so I muted and yelling at
her to be quiet and I mean there's like
in Soviet in Soviet Russia I mean I mean
in schools they were required to read
Marx and in linen and you would think
those ideas would would inspire you know
the system and it did a system like that
project Argos like in the late 50s and
that got shut down by the oligarchs in
power and so I mean that's that's always
the question that comes up when I when I
say okay well we we need a post-scarcity
society or free X it's like okay well
there's gonna be people that that always
want to take power you know and what do
you do about that so how would you
answer that question
well and that is one of the downfalls of
something like Marxism where the idea is
you pass control over to an elite
whatever that elite means group of
people and they fix it to the point it
doesn't mean that central authority and
then you know the people can take
/ and nothing ever gets to that point
because nobody gives up Authority and
nobody in that position does that and so
my solution is we never do that you
never have a central authority of people
who has more power than the rest I mean
a technology company right now
technology companies are powerful they
own our data they have all the money
they have all our information but what
we can create together isn't is more
powerful but it's not power over its
power with we can create more dynamic
and trustworthy tools that we want to
put our information in and me wait so we
don't need to hand over we don't need a
new government right if Google gave us
all of the tools we needed but was it
was a benevolent company that we all we
all were part of and we could all could
transparently see everything they do
they don't really have power over only
power with they would only be able to
say hey here's this news you know um
Julie we could you you could use your
data in what would get you to use it
here what would do we need to have in
place you trust it so it's usable so
it's safe it's not telling you no laws
on how to live your life it's in fact
asking you how can we make the tools for
you to live a better and better life
because everyone involved is a member
everyone you don't like we all want
those tools so it's just about
co-creating those tools together not
about giving up our power or our
sovereignty to a central authority there
will probably at least in the beginning
be a central like a Board of Directors
that runs the technology company unless
we can figure out a better governance
system than that and honestly I think we
absolutely can like having a board of
directors it's run with liquid democracy
but people aren't interest and they just
want a group of people to run with it
and go with it as long as they're doing
that openly and transparently that and
of itself will be a game changer and but
not handing over authority for our lives
other to another group of people and so
the there is a real
risk to the existing powers that be not
wanting this to be in place right that's
always gonna be a risk but that's why it
can't rely on one person it has to be
decentralized it has to be something
that anyone can come and be part of and
co-create together it's not one central
authority or figurehead saying this is
how it should be done
this is how it has to be done it's who
are you what is your project who are
your people what is the bigger
organization it needs to exist in order
to be able to facilitate that and
co-creating it together from the ground
up and that's something that if it falls
apart can restart again and again and
again because it's about using the tools
of gay Bay against gay Bay in my opinion
so so I guess I guess the the challenge
is really like making a making a
collaborative tool that everyone can use
virtually to create a system but but
then you know once you have that I mean
because we that doesn't really exist I
mean there's a company like auto auto
cad or autodesk yeah Autodesk and I mean
like si P a that could be you know used
and it's you know inspire those sorts of
systems to be used to create clever tech
tech development tool and then after
that then then so right now as far as I
could see no one no one's interested in
collaborating as a group maybe because
there's a lack of plat of a platform so
it's like you gotta have a participation
but you also have the platform right you
can't just be a great great artist I
mean I'm I'm a busker by trade or was so
you know you could be a great musician
but you know you know if there's no one
there then nothing happens so yeah
that's a challenge
and then once you do then then how do
you motivate these people to do do so
much because there's few there's there's
a few amount of expertise or people
interested in and and developing these
tools already so it's just a matter of
like how do you how do you track them
it's it to build it how do you find the
people who want to actually build it you
mean like how do you find good tech
workers the people to create the
platform or yeah where are they they're
everywhere but did it if in order to
work on somebody else's project that
isn't ours that wasn't generated
together you have to pay them and you
have to pay them really well yeah if
they're part of generating the idea if
you have the tech skills to be able to
code it and you're able to create what
it could look like together then you're
also feeding into that can I make this
and so there's gonna be people who are
involved in that process who are the
people who are like yes I can make this
I can make this piece of it I can make
this piece of it and working together to
figure out how we can have a bunch of
people working on their own project and
somehow it still comes together to
create as a whole right like all the
different little pieces fit together to
be something that the individual user
actually can use and part of it is
figuring out that process with the
people who are in the tech industry what
would make this this job in this
contribution worthwhile what kind of
tools could make it worthwhile what kind
of Job Description what kind of teams
what do you what do you need to make
this happen what do you want how can we
great which is kind of what together
Tech is doing right is it's bringing the
projects together and saying how do we
create that's a lot of the people in
projects are tech people are people who
have their own tech project whatever
piece of it they can do they just don't
have the full piece you know I mean
they're not the marketer and the tech
person and and all it fits everything
all in one package cuz I forgot the
question
know that that's the answer so really
okay and that doesn't like yeah which
which answers you know both questions
like then how does it get executed and
and having the marketing people and so
on and one easy answer would be like
we'll provide everyone with the basic
income but then it's like how where's
the political momentum for that I mean
we're seeing it now really because we
are seeing yeah it does it might be
something comes out of this for sure so
yeah if people have remained locked in
and have a decent income where they can
they can continue to explore these ideas
and I think they'll just continue
continue to accelerate that process and
having you be I would be definitely
helpful but I don't think we rely on it
I mean I wasn't planning on cope at 19
and everyone being inside to happen
before it did happen so that wasn't the
goal you know I mean that wasn't like I
needed this to happen order to institute
at solutions cooperative you take
positive yeah yeah we might get you bi
we might do but I think together we can
solve you bi
better than our governments not in like
right now how it has to look is
basically our governments you can figure
out how they get money to give money to
each citizen right either based on needs
or based on just everyone that's 2000
everyone gets 4000 whatever the number
is per month and that requires them to
have a lot it's a really expensive
system I mean where are they getting the
money from especially right now what if
this goes on for years the what a
hyperinflation like what are we doing we
don't really understand the complexity
of the system and yet or how to feed
ourselves we can figure out how to
shelter ourselves and figure out how to
create clothes and how to have a supply
chain that we mean in order to be able
to live the lives we live and have them
be equitable right have it be that we're
not living off of slavery in the misery
of others and the destruction of our
planet but how do we actually create
something that gets our needs met a lot
of our wants met and everybody can
thrive in and that's something we can
kind of only create together like my
only option to feed clothe healthcare
educate is to become rich and
someone else to do those things yeah if
there's other options available that
aren't our current model of buying
everything and solving everything and
having transactions as relationships
instead it's what's kind of happy
happening naturally during this pandemic
people are bored and they're looking to
do good and they're looking to help and
there's also enough arias players and
it's like all of it's happening
simultaneously but there's the good part
happening in that good part can actually
grow and create something that the
nefarious characters can't really
with they just can't like especially
when we're all connected and we know
what's going on and we understand and we
haven't left life or death decisions up
to our governments that are clearly
incompetent I mean they're not yeah the
best the best we have they're not really
you have going on I mean if the bonds
are tight communally if there's a real
you know if we really have communal love
then it's unstoppable
there's no like you know as you say
nefarious people to take advantage there
because because everything's so tight
Annette it's like okay what do you do
might just just play video game or
something you know if you want to do
that
I'm still here if you want to add to
that that was a question sir I can't
repeat the question no no it wasn't a
question I was just adjusting just
adjusting the screen so yeah tell me but
your project what is it that you I mean
I read here that Google Doc yeah but the
governance system and and such how do
you see it moving forward how do you see
it ever actually being implemented what
part I guess like how the road map to
how we would get there yeah the road map
well yeah this this is a good
opportunity once locked in to in your
ideas cafe I think is great and that can
be used like as a as like a virtual
salon or or like sandbox I'll send you a
link to a web a website that can that
can promote can promote this if you're
interested in doing it and basically
like bringing people together and kind
of fleshing out okay what what would a
project cybersyn 2.0 be like and or a
resource-based economy that might put
some people off the resource-based
economy thing because because then you
have to deal delve into like the
calculation problem and in jobs or
having a role in society which I think
could be done I think you can it you
could as long as you address those first
thing and say okay this will be you know
this will be a you know we'll just be
talking transitional phase etc because
because you want it you want to bring
everyone in I mean as far as I could
tell the resource-based economy has put
a lot of people off because it's it's
such it's such a heart it's such it's so
much at once I mean their model is like
you know centralizing and and creating
these massive cities that's kind of
inspired by The Venus Project you know
and doing doing it somehow with zero
money so that's like that's like
you know and just way too challenging so
so basically yet doing it doing it in
phases and and trying to track every one
of any any political ideology to build
this so so I mean maybe this you know I
think a marketer would say say it's a
it's a it's a question of branding and
you know psychology needs to get
involved too but but maybe not I mean
because because the pandemic has been
such a bonding moment I think for a lot
of people hopefully none of that
trickery manipulation will have to be
necessary to get people involved in this
and and I mean people I mean trickery
only last for so long it's it's uh it's
really about you know what what at the
core do we really want and I think at
the core we all we all want to be cared
for and loved so and love each other or
I think a lot a lot of us need to work
on that you know myself included so just
just kind of like working at that core
and then building it from there a system
that is essentially becomes a part of
the internet so that we can live freely
so it might sound a bit baked so please
please s like questions like if you want
to know something more specific I don't
really have I mean when I read it
through usually there are things are
like this is absolutely not possible
because I read a lot of people's
world-changing ideas some of which are
better than others
and there was nothing there I didn't
even take notes because there was
nothing there I was like oh this isn't
feasible this isn't but it was also
besides the problems I have with
anything which is like how do we
actually get there
right like I mean one of the most
promising projects that are really
really like is Renzi's common planet
which is an idea for a currency that
when you spend it it goes away and
everyone gets a amount per day and you
get X amount based on when you sign into
the system and it's interesting that
it's like well yes and he does have a
road to get there which is basically we
sign up for there's a game and then when
there's enough throw out 12 of people
who would do this then it tips over into
that but that system in and of itself is
like right but how do you get that
number of people on there right like the
game itself then has to be interesting
enough and marketable enough in order
for people to come on board and be part
of that in order for their ever to be
that threshold of people to be able to
tip it over into the system and I don't
have a lot of faith in anything that has
to be that big to begin with even though
as someone who has a that big vision if
it can't be like if there's no road map
to get there and there's a there to get
to that's kind of part of it and part of
the problem is is then you're with the
destination of mine you're going to take
different decisions and create different
things than if it's it's about moving
from here and I get it cuz I'm working
in both directions like I have the big
vision it's like how can we get there
from here then I have this like well
this is the next step I can see how it
leads to the big vision but there's very
few projects that incorporate like that
are actually feasible now and big and
world-changing and so I never know like
cryptocurrency is really cool but I
don't think we're ever going to
implement it because we already have our
lack of trust in our monetary system
and so something that is both more
complex and less understandable to the
average everyday person needs to be like
way more trustworthy and simplistic like
in order for us to adopt it it can't
just be better it has to be better in
like every scenario and if it's
something that has to be implemented and
then and then tested on a grand scale
then there's so much room for
catastrophe and so much room for human
misery that it has to be you know I mean
like as much as I would sign up for a
resource-based economy tomorrow I can
only imagine it would be a beautiful
wonderful world I don't know that to be
the case right if I woke up torn we
lived in one and I can foresee a
dystopian society there right I don't
know what that would look like because
that's not my vision of what a
resource-based economy is but it could
be like we don't know all of the
repercussions and every ripple that
happens when you change something and so
the best thing to do is create a system
that changes things a system that
continually improves a system that
everyone can be involved in as much or
as little as they want to and being
involved is its own reward as well as
helping to move forward as its own
reward so that you want to be part of it
like I mean no one has to force us to be
on Facebook or on Netflix or on YouTube
we don't do it for society's benefit if
it can be that easy and that rewarding
in an entertainment fashion to be part
of creating a better world you're not
gonna be short of volunteers you're not
gonna be short of people who want to be
part of it and you're giving them the
heartstring part right and you're
selling them a better world people would
do that because they do all the time
just with that vision but I'm not
answering your question at all I'm sorry
that what you were asked being asked
questions on I don't know what if I have
questions about it in particular for
that reason that there's like like the
governance structure there was something
about it that reminded me I don't know
you wouldn't know because you're not
part of game be this guy Jasper Skye he
wrote an article on fractal democracy
and I had a conversation with him which
you could watch it's on my youtube
channel his is his
public and the idea is basically
everything is tied so you have a group
of seven people the group of seven
people elect one of you to go be part of
the next group of seven of seven and
some and so a country like the United
States I think has eight levels so 7 ^ 8
because I think maybe this popular
states I might be wondering one or two
off but you basically meet with them in
periodic time see me with your group of
seven every other two months and if
you're elected meet with all of these
groups all the way down the line so if
you're like there is no president even
if here with the president you're
meeting with the like group of seven
that's in charge of the place plus
you're meeting with all your people all
the way down and there was something
about that that I was like it seems not
similar to yours but there was something
maybe explain your governance system and
then yeah it sounds very similar I mean
that this is the this is thing like I'm
very sympathetic to the left and and I
think the left is finally getting over
the anti-technology
you know love ISM quite a lot especially
now so I think that's helpful so so like
because because I really want to peel -
to the left I you know I have to make
sure to preface that yes I mean there's
gonna be centralization but also also it
afford you know it also be a distributed
system and unique unique unique things
can happen within you know very unique
groups and renew these groups can be
very exclusive if they want to be or
very open and and because the system so
open it be able to allow for you know a
bunch of exclusive groups that maybe
don't want to share anything though
see the fractal democracy sounds sounds
very similar the in the political system
it is basically a council framework a
federated council framework was kind of
inspired through anarchist communism or
whatever you want to call it I'm vaiting
but so essentially be like a small group
of experts in every single every single
field of expertise that would just play
the role of making sure that everyone's
in the know basically being facilitators
for for the rest of technique food just
want to work on tech I mean in my
experience most most techies do not want
to get involved in politics I just want
to work on my thing and not be bothered
so so these these people would would
would be in that role to make sure that
they can keep to do their thing while
it's well still while they're still not
being taken advantage of I mean they
basically be you know the protectors of
you know protectors of that creativity
and and try to try to amplify that and
and creating progress for other people
to attract attract people to becoming
more creative essentially techies are
basically created people who is
expertise decided on he said there's
like a panel of experts but how besides
on expertise I mean at first it would be
self organized and but as these things
happen as group as groups as people as
people like you know form a group as the
group goes on it does start to ossify
you know get rigid and and and start to
an issue but I mean initially the theory
goes that you know people will just self
organize and create these these systems
spontaneously obviously there needs to
be a platform that they can thicken they
can build on that's that's on the
internet so I think that's that's like
the first step to do that and I was
gonna ask you if you'd be interested in
hosting something like that too
to get that going like as a salon or
something in it I know a website that
can promote it that hopefully can bring
a lot of people into to build their so
so essentially it's just you know self
selected but if there if there is a
problem if people using the system say
there's a problem then there needs to be
some way to to to correct it and get
these these you know replace these these
people if they're if they're being like
if they are restricting the system or
being a bottleneck in some way and that
could be done through sortition which
would which would then like bring in
other experts relates to that field that
are knowledgeable or that field that can
understand ok this is why the this is
why there is that problem right there
not just you met you know managers that
just don't know understand the problem
maybe actually experts in the field that
that could then you know dispute you
know Nick just you know negotiate
hopefully negotiate the problem but but
might need to to actually replace that
person there's issue
hopefully that wouldn't be much of a
problem but but there of course that
question needs to be answered like how
do you how do you how do you prevent
these these people from just being the
new you lead the new the new power
grabbers and so on so that's that's how
far I've gone with that I'm not really
experts in in positions of power yes I
think that it gives I mean what example
do you know of experts in business is a
power me ally they like people in charge
of the university people in charge of
getting people into or out of medical
school people like when there's
gatekeepers as to you're either part of
this group or you're not part of this
group your experts you're not experts I
believe in if people want to be with
elite groups they should get to do that
so if you are scholarly and you only
want to talk to other people who are you
consider scholarly than great let's
facilitate that but I want everyone
personally like everyone at every level
if you're interested in history I don't
actually care if you're an expert
history how do we get but then there
does come a point where for certain
systems it makes sense to have a panel
of experts and a few will be able to
weigh in on it on a different level I
mean I mean sort of so the argument
argument I posed it's like you know you
want an experienced surgeon to top right
on you if you if you have a medical
problem yeah you don't want just someone
off the street that's like enthusiastic
about surgery to perform it so yeah I
would say like in most cases like yeah
these people need to be invisible they
need to be like not a part of my life
right but to like if you come into like
needing certain things to happen or to
have complex technologies to work yeah
with without without corporate without
corporations then there needs to be some
some level of management until until we
have like you know the technological
singularity or you know AI that's you
know AGI and and those sorts of
technologies that can then take over
from from these from this panel and then
and then there'd be no need for an
expert panel
it'd just be completely like feedback
based decision making where no one no
one really votes it's just like the
people vote with their actions right and
the actions are so I mean they're not
voting they're just acting and then
decisions are made within the system
that gets that that is pleasurable for
everyone I mean and how far I mean I do
you follow AI
I mean I know you have a few i watch
twenty of videos and I saw your your you
had a you're talking to a few software
engineers and I'm just just curious when
you think when you think will achieve
AGI
I've no idea that's not my area of
expertise at all I just have like
algorithm will do this magic and other
things I think you're the experts are
like very conservative because they're
there they're deep in the trenches and
are like yeah who knows 100 years who
knows right so I mean I mean I read like
Raymond Kurzweil book the singularities
in the year like in 2006 and and that
book really blew my mind
it was quite I mean this was before
these ideas were pretty well known in
2006 but I saw really scary you know
being a mystic I I could I could read
between the lines and see what what he
was really advocating for and it's quite
scary terrifying you know right wing
acceleration ism you know I mean have
you seen like Batman Forever
I don't remember it it was like yeah it
was
it's like Jim Carrey you know as the
Riddler basically was in this machine
that you know sucked everyone's thoughts
and controlled everyone like zombies and
that's kind of the vision I got while
reading his book and that's you know
that's something something we want to
avoid having having a system that could
they could lead to someone being that
that powerful able able to manipulate or
control everyone in that manner yeah
it's where like for me personally I
don't want to create anything I wouldn't
want to create a panel I wouldn't want
to be part of that's not rewarding in
and of itself but I also don't want to
create a panel that I'm not part of
right like if I'm not on that panel of
experts and what are the chances I am
that means they it how much power do
they have over my life
right and over the technology that's
created in the course of things how can
I take power back from them how can if
they do something wrong what's what's
there to stop them from acting variously
because getting seven people on board
with each other if there's if there's um
I know I decided there were seven look
isn't the thing I said about
I mentioned 7y
but however many people right it's not
fine whatever your favorite not getting
them all on board together it's not that
difficult if there's something in it for
them right for them to be in goods with
each other and I don't want anyone to
have a position of power over me
including my own politicians that's
where I want to create it I want to
create a system or I want to be involved
in creating a system
someone needs to create a system and I
want to be part of it it's unfair to say
that yeah I can have complete control
over my own life as long as I'm not
inflicting hard about other people and I
can house nobody else that I'm not
choosing to be part of have control over
me and I don't choose to be part of
Canada so I don't want it to have any
power over me that I'm choosing to live
in Vancouver that's a little more
accurate and so anything we create
locally I'm you know like I'm choosing
to be here or I can move somewhere else
to have beyond her own governance but
anyway that's just like into my decision
making is is although anything I
actually create I'm probably gonna at
least start on the board of I want to
design it as if I'm the millionth member
right the millionth person coming in who
doesn't know how the inside information
yes they do because everyone does write
it like doesn't have any power yeah they
do they have the same power so you know
they have their vote they have their
they can have a say and what tools are
created and what what ways we improve
the tools we do have yes I think that's
a great goal and go into that stage
where software basically just just reads
what you know mmm
knows knows what you need and knows what
you know a whole variety of people in
your area need and can just make these
decisions autonomously without even
knowing how the system works so these
experts like yeah I mean I mean ideally
would would be would really not not like
to be in a position of power these are
people that
sort of out of out of care for those for
everyone are doing it they're doing it
out of out of out of love rather than
like power seating so that that's that's
the ideal right those are the ideal
people you you want to have because
these are people in and I mean maybe
expertise is it's kind of a tricky word
isn't it but you know deep knowledge and
experience on a subject so that's that's
what I mean by expertise you know so to
take care for others to be basically
mentors for for the rest of the people
working in that field to be able to to
spread their their creative endeavors
across the world and make them an option
for the world is is ideally what I'd
like to see or would intend for such a
panel but of course like technology in
our pastors in our recent past hundred
years as has been used for nefarious
ends so that that's always something to
be really aware of as as you design
these systems to make sure that they
they can't be co-opted and and that they
somehow can also remind people to
address address their own internal
internal workings alright and that that
I think that is something that deeply
needs to be explored in and as we move
forward our our deep internal
motivations for why we do things I think
those are good those are address that we
find the right people that that we can
love and be loved by and we're all just
we're all loving community then or at
least you know potentially or everyone's
a potential like you know what I mean
no one's out to get you that you know
sort of a gift economy or true gift
economy kind of perspectives and then
then the risk of this of this panel
which which would just be temporary
let's look at you know bring things
bring things through to post-scarcity
condition mm-hmm I think I forgot how
people get on to the expert panel
because there's like they who's on the
expert panel like what expertise sit on
that panel
why are though why those and not the
other people right is there one
scientist is there seven scientists
because there's like seven different
kinds of science like how many mm-hm who
are the experts but also how do they he
said something I think it was my version
an algorithm decides on who the expert
is and I think they would like invite
them as opposed to them say is that
right but instead it like do I say I
want to be on the expert panel or did
someone say hey Jubilee would he go or
invited to be on the expert panel I mean
this I mean at the moment where we stand
it'd be self selected but I mean or an
algorithm would be a great idea as well
like okay let's listen and I just admit
if they eye is that smart okay you know
and so it's kind of like okay where we
are at the level of the capability of a
high but yeah I mean AI then hey I
addressed it okay people people say the
or X experts feel that they're still
needed to manage these area the area
then DNA could be used to select them at
some at some point when a nice capable
enough yeah that's a great question you
mentioned like okay how many expert
panels will there be and so basically I
mentioned like basically every
discipline and so that's a lot panels
and and then somehow you know networking
them all the where they all know each
other's field and and this being like
open data I mean I assume completely
that the data is gonna be open so that
it could it can you know also feed into
algorithms or AI I'll just say
algorithms instead because the eyes kind
of a tricky tricky concept but and and
then be able to
- then you know creating algorithm that
doesn't require these these panels
because that that's that's eventually
gonna be a bottleneck I think right now
could it could actually accelerate
things okay but eventually that will
become a bottleneck and yeah or you know
the panel will just say okay we're not
needed anymore
and if we need to meet up we'll meet up
kind of thing and it again would be self
selected are they on the panel like
today that today I'm not seeing anyone
self selected to do this self selecting
so looks like it'd require money yeah
and where's that money gonna come from
you know who's gonna pay the money yeah
that's always a good question I'm just
gonna be in charge she's gonna be doing
what and where is money coming from or
resources not working in money yeah I
mean money's controlled by the financial
industry that's hijacked the government
right so at this stage is just it's just
finding I think crowdsourcing I find
incredibly unethical because you're
essentially asking the poor to take care
of the poor but it's all we got really
so so crowdsourcing sorry meaning um
like I need a new kidney and it come
across fifty thousand so crowd fund me
some money or crowd sourcing like hey we
all need kidneys how do we get us all
kidneys and someone come up with an idea
or someone coming up with let's all pool
our money and everyone puts in ten
thousand dollars a month a month it was
ten thousand dollars love a lifetime and
then you're guaranteed a kidney out of
it like what do you mean by
crowdsourcing well yeah as it works
today it's like individuals asking you
know other visuals for money and in a
stock you know it's like out of
desperation really and it's it's
unethical because
you're asking a bunch of disadvantaged
mostly disadvantaged or you know poor
people to fund other people and it
should be that the wealthy the wealthy
should have more responsibility filling
me for responsibility to to that however
they shouldn't be in a system that that
creates such outrageous inequality to
begin with alright so those are the
challenges yeah I mean I think that the
the rich are not who I mean any one rich
person could fund any of the ideas that
I've come across that are world world
changing world safety and any celebrity
can endorse it it could you know go
viral overnight but my money my that's
not how we do it I mean I didn't I say I
agree with you the crowdsourcing in that
way is unethical and it's like well it's
a popularity contest but you get to live
or die isn't that nice um yeah
but having crowdsourcing crowdfunding
solutions necessary to actually help
create solutions so not hey I need food
someone give me food because I can't
make it to my next payday and then
there's enough money to go around
instead hey how do we feed ourselves how
do we not how do we so my my basic
funding model for the reason it's 10,000
people on hundred thousand dollars is
that people are putting in ten dollars
to the pool never deciding what to do
with that hundred our our one hundred
thousand dollars that we self-funded
together that's enough that it's not
most people poor or not can afford ten
dollars if we're doing it ten dollars a
month
most people can afford that as well and
it's not from the rich and it's not it's
crowdsource but it's creating solutions
that actually bring down our cost of
living right we're not we're not even
creating solutions for the benefit of
other people we're creating solutions
for ourselves right how do we feed
ourselves for cheaper how do we close
ourselves for cheaper how do we
understand what shelter to use how do we
create governance system
that we want to be part of how do we get
in sources of information that we want
to actually use and I don't my brain
already I need to go operate that's a
step that's a step in the right
direction for sure yeah yeah it sounds
like a good transitional stuff mm-hmm
like I mean Bernie Sanders although he
just dropped out had some of the biggest
money contributions and they were all
$20 donations from people from well
Americans because you can't get
donations if you're not an American
can't get their nations from non
Americans but he even had in the
hundreds of millions of dollars in 20
that can't be right 19 20 dollar amounts
there's like 300 million yeah what do
you look for in yeah whatever I'm not
doing that bath right now I'm having
people who like if if my language is
well I'm poor so I don't have money and
someone else needs to solve this for me
the rich ought to that's true on many
many levels why are they rich it should
be on them but at the same time if I'm
not willing to take on ten dollars a
month for my own benefit the benefit of
everyone else if I'm not willing to put
$10 into a pool for a one-time project
then well don't say about that
like if it's it like we there's a hell
of a lot we can do together that doesn't
require us to go through the gatekeepers
of the rich and powerful or get people
elected or create a new governance
system and we can do most of it from
right now right here especially right
now right here about everyone's second
size that crowdsourcing idea is really
great especially especially if it's an
under condition of a view bi know then
people would have you know plenty plenty
of money to spare you know given that
the UB is substantial enough and then
it's just a matter of attracting people
to the idea if it's a great idea and
then there's people ready ready to work
on that idea just just needing the money
so
yeah we got the idea it is you know the
benefits everything I think that's a
great that's a great transitional step
what's your progress on that so far
I mean I'm not even in a state where I
would be able to accept money from other
people because unless I'm getting it I
don't want to get in anything unless
there's an us to get it there's not
enough to spend it because I just it
just makes my life much more complex to
be getting that too complex it's not
worth it for me to have to fill out the
paperwork have to fill out and but it's
just about that's why we're doing the
solution raising because if you can get
people to truly understand it with
10,000 people we could create this any
of them with $100,000 if we each put in
$10 then you have the people like it
needs to be at that level right having
people trickle in and having a dozen
people putting ten dollars isn't gonna
do anything you need thousands and
thousands of people to be putting in $10
and then it's it Aloha nuf right it has
to be something they want to create
together that's gonna benefit them and
so it's just about figuring out which of
the solution raisins which idea
generates the buzz to the point of we
need to actually create this I mean at
the end of every single one I'm like
yeah this could be done like I wanted to
do people don't want to have them out of
the meta conversation the conversation
the conversation the project rates are
crazy no sorry the solution raising on
solution raising they want to have the
ones that they feel impact their life
more I don't remember if that was my
brain is shutting down I'm gonna have to
go yes I'm really nonverbal yeah that's
but I'm always free to engage with meta
meta conversations I love that stuff all
right sounds sounds good
we're doing solution raisins at 8:30 in
the morning on Wednesday is 8:30 my time
so seven or eight hours later for time
4:00 in the afternoon that kind of
worked out of my brain maybe yeah or an
afternoon or 13:00 afternoon good thirty
yeah okay yeah no I'll check that out
then all right I'm just gonna say
goodbye to YouTube here bye YouTube you
decide what we can do it